# Mohammad Mustakim Hassan

Full-stack Developer

I am a final year ( Graduation 2022 Dec ) student working as a full stack software developer. I have been developing professionally for half a year and have longer experience working with front end technologies as a freelancer. Although I have found my strongest skills are in backend development and it is there I do my best. I can help everywhere in the stack and I love wearing multiple hats to an extent.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Team Contact, Remote** — Full Stack Developer

NOV 2020 - PRESENT

Following waterfall, agile software development life cycle model and methodologies, I have worked with a team to deliver our clients clients -

- Monolithic single vendor ecommerce.
- Inventory software for chain medical pharma stores.
- Website for a restaurant with order and catering service.
- Enterprise Resource Planning Web Application.

# **Elephant Communication, Dhaka** — Web Developer

JUN 2021 - DEC 2021

Elephant Communication is a creative tech agency based in Dhaka, Bangladesh. At elephant we offer creative & tech solutions to your brand and business through our strategic and effective approach.

My responsibility at elephant was to -

- Provide Tech Solution for clients
- Developing CMS/ Monolithic solution as required

### **Contact**, **Remote** — Freelancer

2017 - 2019

I started out at online websites with PSD to HTML conversion, content writing & managing social media. I quickly moved on to developing websites with WordPress, wix. Within a short time I found myself writing scripts in different languages to automate random small things clients wanted - google sheets, excel macros, JavaScript rss feed watcher etc. I have also made logos for offline clients on request. My most memorable project was a short animated educational advertisement video I made with Adobe Illustrator and PowerPoint.

283 Free School Street, Khatalbagan Dhaka, 1205 (+88) 01890316871 mmhshayer@gmail.com viceroyshayer.github.io

#### **SKILLS**

Language -

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, SQL

Frontend -

Vue, NuxtJs

Backend -

NodeJs, ExpressJs, NestJs

Database -

MongoDB, MySQL, PostgresQl, TypeORM, Sequalizer, redis

Tools -

Git, Docker, insomnia/postman.

Interested to learn -

Angular, ASP.NET CORE 6 (C# ecosystem), GCP/AWS, python.

### **LANGUAGES**

Bengali - Native

English - Fluent

Chinese - Working Knowledge

I did almost anything I could because I loved the thrill of the challenge. It was a very fun journey which helped me grow, taught me professionalism, made me realistic and bought me where I am now.

### **EDUCATION**

# **Hubei University of Science & Technology,** Wuhan, China — *B.Eng Computer Science*

FEB 2019 - Dec 2022

Will be graduating Q1 2023. Current GPA - 3.25.

### **Notre Dame College**, Dhaka —*HSC*

JUN 2012 - JUN 2014

Fr. Benjamin Costa's last batch and Dr. Fr Hemanto Pius Rozario's First. Graduated with a GPA - 5 overall, Group - Science, English Version.

# **Dhaka Public School**, Dhaka — SSC

JUN 2011 - JUN 2012

Graduated with a GPA - 5 overall, Group - Science, English Version.

### **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

### English Drama Teacher, ANHUI — HBUT's Green Light

JUN 2019 - JUL 2019

In a 3 week long volunteer program taught children English, English drama to children In Qixi village, Anhui Province, China.

# Campaign Volunteer, DHAKA— JAAGO Foundation

OCT 2015

World Day of the Handicapped is also known as the International Day of People with Disability (IDPD). It is observed on 3 December to raise awareness about understanding and accepting people with disabilities.

### **REFERENCE**

**Rusho Khan** from *Elephant Communication* 

Email: the\_rusho@hotmai Phone: +8801709288481